## MELISSA MEPHAM







#### **WEB DEV - DESIGNER**

021 087 32005 aplaceofdreams.co.nz aplaceofdreams.herokuapp.com github.com/MelMepham m.a.mepham@gmail.com github.com/MelMepham www.linkedin.com/in/melissaMepham

I am writing this as an accomplished visual artist, trained graphic designer and front end developer (in training).

I am a lover of animated films with Tomm Moore being one of my favorite directors. His attention to detail, use of colour and storytelling skills are mind blowing, and has been a constant form of inspiration for me over the last two years.

I hold myself with a high level of integrity and care most about the people I surround myself with. I am looking for full time employment that will strengthen my skills as a front end developer, as well as being involved in a creative, inspiring, and dynamic team.

- **Problem Solver** Design is problem solving. In the 10 years since embarking on my journey into the design world I have been constantly utilizing the skills I have learnt, leading to strong problem solving skills.
- **Giving and receiving feedback** Over the past 3 months I have been immersed in an environment that was focused on developing strong skills on how to give and receive feedback.
- Working in a diverse team environment At Fidel's I was responsible for managing a team of 45 diverse staff members, and excelled in this environment.
- Work ethic Throughout my career, my high level of integrity and care for my work has led to employers developing a high level of trust, and increased responsibilities.
- Extensive Adobe suite skills I have been using the Adobe suite for 10 years.
- **Technologies and tools** Knowledge of JS, Node.js, Express.js, Webpack, React, Redux, CSS, SCSS, Git, SQLite, Knex, Enzime, Functional JS, Test driven Development.
- Unit Testing We used the Jest test suite for our testing at EDA (Enspiral Dev Academy).
- Strong eye for design I love typography and this requires a strong attention to detail.
- Great at dealing with conflict Throughout my hospitality career I dealt with a range of conflicts that arose and focused on allowing people to be heard, quickly defusing any difficult situations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Enspiral Dev Academy November 2017 – March 2018

Web Dev Apprenticeship

Enspiral Dev Academy is an intense learning environment that's like an apprenticeship on steroids. Over three months I have learnt how to create fully fledged web apps, as well as a vast array of human skills.

I personally found my love for front end development and a passion for UI and UX. I am so excited to enter into the tech industry to learn, grow and be an amazing addition to an existing team.

The EDA environment was diverse, supportive and focused heavily on team work. EDA taught industry relevant technologies and focusing on continued learning, and making a positive impact on the world.

## Freelance May 2017 – January 2018

**Artist / Graphic Designer** 

I left Fidel's and worked as a freelance artist and designer, I was able to work with some amazing startups and existing businesses, as well as hosting a successful solo exhibition, along with a multitude of personal projects.

Through this time I started to explore tech as a medium for my art and realised how valuable and transferable my creative skills would be in the tech industry, which led me to EDA.

# MELISSA MEPHAM







#### **WEB DEV - DESIGNER**

021 087 32005 aplaceofdreams.co.nz aplaceofdreams.herokuapp.com github.com/MelMepham m.a.mepham@gmail.com github.com/MelMepham www.linkedin.com/in/melissaMepham

## Kiwiburn Arts Festival January 2017 – Current

Arts Committee Chair (volunteer role)

I manage a team of 5 and we are responsible for promoting the availability of both large and small art grants as well as an innovation and a community grant. We also review and distribute the grants to a pre set of criteria.

This is an amazing opportunity to support the local creative community as well as inspiring and promoting young artists to explore their ideas and concepts in a supportive environment.

R & C Holdings, Wellington (Fidel's Cafe, Havana Bar, Havana Brothers Bakehouse) In-House Graphic Designer December 2016 – May 2017

When I left Fidel's, the owners didn't want to lose me so created an in-house Graphic Design job for me.

I worked closely with their three businesses to develop graphic design solutions, here I discovered the barrier the lack of technical knowledge was having on me professionally.

### Fidel's Cafe, Wellington January 2015 – December 2016

General Manager

I returned from Australia and came back with the concept of following a creative career, I was hired by Fidel's as a cafe worker, and fell in love with the business, the people and the culture. I was given more autonomy as time went on and when the General Manager position came up, I saw it as an amazing opportunity and was promoted. During this time, I:

- managed a team of 45,
- hired over 20 staff members,
- saw a solid increase in profits and worked toward meeting KPI's,
- developed training manuals,
- dealt with all disputes and complaints with integrity, and
- managed the Payroll and all HR requirements.

Various Hospitality Positions around Australia May 2006 – December 2014 Barista / Supervisor / Floor Staff

## **EDUCATION**

Web Development (see experience for more details)

2017 - 2018

Enspiral Dev Academy, Wellington, New Zealand.

Bachelor of Visual Communication Design (Hons)

2007 - 2011

Massey University, Wellington, New Zealand. (Graduated May 2012)

Diploma in Computer Graphic Design

2006 - 2007

Natcoll Design Technology, Wellington, New Zealand.

## **REFERENCE**

Available on Request